<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubernetes on Jamie&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://akjamie.github.io/tags/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Jamie&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://akjamie.github.io/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CKA &amp; important operation commands</title>
      <link>http://akjamie.github.io/post/2023-05-29-k8s-cka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://akjamie.github.io/post/2023-05-29-k8s-cka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Complains about the CKA exam:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The CKA exam environment was changed from Terminal to Remote Desktop(VNC) from Last Jun, this is an absolutely shit&lt;br&gt;&#xA;decision. The huge lagging causes that large amount of candidate&amp;rsquo;s time-wasting on always-waiting, and also Mouse is&#xA;nearly useless - very difficult to locate what you want on Firefox browser, and eventually it highlights the good user&#xA;experience on the k8s built-in documentation - &lt;strong&gt;Kubectl explain&lt;/strong&gt;, how ridiculous it is !!!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explore Kubernetes Local PV &amp; PVC access mode</title>
      <link>http://akjamie.github.io/post/2023-04-08-k8s-pv-pvc-access-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://akjamie.github.io/post/2023-04-08-k8s-pv-pvc-access-mode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A local volume represents a mounted local storage device such as a disk, partition or directory.&#xA;Local volumes can only be used as a statically created PersistentVolume. Dynamic provisioning is not supported.&#xA;Compared to hostPath volumes, local volumes are used in a durable and portable manner without manually scheduling pods&#xA;to nodes. The system is aware of the volume&amp;rsquo;s node constraints by looking at the node affinity on the PersistentVolume.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vault Agent with Kubernetes</title>
      <link>http://akjamie.github.io/post/2023-03-26-vault-agent-with-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://akjamie.github.io/post/2023-03-26-vault-agent-with-k8s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;challenge&#34;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nearly all requests to Vault must be accompanied by an authentication token. This includes all API requests, as well as&#xA;via the Vault CLI and other libraries. If you can securely get the first secret from an originator to a consumer,&#xA;all subsequent secrets transmitted between this originator and consumer can be authenticated with the trust&#xA;established by the successful distribution and user of that first secret.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The applications running in a Kubernetes environment is no exception. Luckily, Vault provides Kubernetes auth method to&#xA;authenticate the clients using a Kubernetes Service Account Token.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vault on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>http://akjamie.github.io/post/2023-03-25-vault-on-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://akjamie.github.io/post/2023-03-25-vault-on-k8s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-vault&#34;&gt;What is Vault?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;vault-introduction&#34;&gt;Vault introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HashiCorp Vault is an identity-based secrets and encryption management system. A secret is anything that you want to tightly&lt;br&gt;&#xA;control access to, such as API encryption keys, passwords, and certificates. Vault provides encryption services that are gated&#xA;by authentication and authorization methods.Using Vault’s UI, CLI, or HTTP API, access to secrets and other sensitive data&#xA;can be securely stored and managed, tightly controlled (restricted), and auditable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes dashboard deployment</title>
      <link>http://akjamie.github.io/post/2022-04-12-kubernetes-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://akjamie.github.io/post/2022-04-12-kubernetes-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;install-dashboard&#34;&gt;Install dashboard&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To run the following command to deploy dashboard&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;kubectl apply -f https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kubernetes/dashboard/v2.5.0/aio/deploy/recommended.yaml&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;once done, to check the resource status under the namespace of kubernetes-dashboard, if all the resources are running, that means dashboard is deployed successfully.&#xA;&lt;img src=&#39;http://akjamie.github.io/img/2022-04-12-kubernetes-dashboard/k8s-dashboard-01.png&#39; style=&#34;height: 484px;margin-left: 0px;&#34;/&gt;&#xA;ps:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On above screenshot, you can see the EXTERNAL-IP for kubernetes-dashboard service,  the reason is i edit the service change the type from ClusterIp to LoadBalancer, and the loadbalancer is backed by Metallb.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brower(Chrome) will block the dasboard access though the https://192.168.58.156 since the tls cert is generated by kubernetes during installation, it can not be trusted by CA, this issue will be resolved in later step.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;generate-tls-cert&#34;&gt;Generate TLS Cert&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Suppose you have already a domain name, or buy a domain name from Alicloud, AWS, or godady,etc.&#xA;Here i will use Alicould for instance, my Domain name is it-meta.space.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
