<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vault on Jamie&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://akjamie.github.io/tags/vault/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vault on Jamie&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://akjamie.github.io/tags/vault/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vault Agent with Kubernetes</title>
      <link>http://akjamie.github.io/post/2023-03-26-vault-agent-with-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://akjamie.github.io/post/2023-03-26-vault-agent-with-k8s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;challenge&#34;&gt;Challenge&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nearly all requests to Vault must be accompanied by an authentication token. This includes all API requests, as well as&#xA;via the Vault CLI and other libraries. If you can securely get the first secret from an originator to a consumer,&#xA;all subsequent secrets transmitted between this originator and consumer can be authenticated with the trust&#xA;established by the successful distribution and user of that first secret.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The applications running in a Kubernetes environment is no exception. Luckily, Vault provides Kubernetes auth method to&#xA;authenticate the clients using a Kubernetes Service Account Token.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vault on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>http://akjamie.github.io/post/2023-03-25-vault-on-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://akjamie.github.io/post/2023-03-25-vault-on-k8s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-vault&#34;&gt;What is Vault?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;vault-introduction&#34;&gt;Vault introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HashiCorp Vault is an identity-based secrets and encryption management system. A secret is anything that you want to tightly&lt;br&gt;&#xA;control access to, such as API encryption keys, passwords, and certificates. Vault provides encryption services that are gated&#xA;by authentication and authorization methods.Using Vault’s UI, CLI, or HTTP API, access to secrets and other sensitive data&#xA;can be securely stored and managed, tightly controlled (restricted), and auditable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
